Guide to the Donald Dombowsky Papers MSS 393
Fales Library and Special Collections
Donald Dombowsky Papers
1977-2011
Fales Library and Special Collections
Dombowsky, Don
MSS 393
3.5 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes, 2 card boxes, and 1 folder in a shared box.
9 audiocassettes
6 sound discs (cd)
Don Dombowsky is a Friedrich Nietzsche scholar and poet who wrote and published poetry under the name Don David in New York City during the late 1980s-90s. The collection contains Dombowsky's correspondence with other writers and artists Dombowksy met during his time in New York. Materials also include manuscripts, publications, and audio recordings created by the writers and artists Dowmbowsky maintained contact with, as well as some of his own work. Materials date from 1977 to 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Donald Dombowsky, 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.393
Arrangement
Maintaining Dombowsky's order, materials are listed alphabetically by author or organization. Unarranged correspondence and unidentified audio recordings are listed at the end.
Biographical Note
Don Dombowsky is a Friedrich Nietzsche scholar and poet who wrote and published poetry under the name Don David in New York City during the late 1980s-90s. During this time he was very involved with the Lower East Side magazine Long News in the Short Century edited by Barbara Henning as well as writers and artists associated with Shiny magazine edited by Michael Friedman.
Originally from Canada, Dombowsky moved to NYC to study philosophy at the New School. He made contact with Dennis Cooper at St. Mark's who put him in touch with Leland Hickman and Kevin Killian who in turn brought him into contact with a range of fascinating poets, writers, publishers, and artists including Paul Buck.
Dombowsky works as an Assistant Professor at Bishop's University, teaching selected topics in the history of philosophy, politics and art.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of Don Dombowsky. A majority of the collection contains Dombowsky's correspondence with writers and artists, including Terrence Sellers, Barbara Henning, and Paul Buck. The collection also contains manuscripts, publications, and audio recordings created by Dombowsky and other writers and artists whom Dombowsky maintained contact with. Materials date from 1977 to 2011.
Poets, Canadian.; Poets, American.; Authors, American.; Authors, Canadian.; Authors and artists.; Artists -- United States.; Dombowsky, Don
- Acker, Kathy, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Barber, Stephen, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Barton, David, 1977-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Buck, Paul, 1979-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
- Buck, Paul: Paul Buck, Melinda Miel - audio recording, 1990; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Buck, Paul: Paul Buck, Allen Fisher, Gilbert A. Dave, David Rushmer - audio recording, undated; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Cole, Norma, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Cussans, John, 1988-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Cussans, John: Frozen Tears, Cracking the Glitch - audio recording, undated; 1 sound disc (cd) (Box Shared Fales 007)
- Custer, Chris, 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3-4, Box Shared Fales 011, Folder 2)
- Don David (Dombowsky), 1985-2006 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Don David (Dombowsky): The Template, The Forgotten Door - audio recording, undated; 1 sound disc (cd) (Box Shared Fales 007)
- Don David (Dombowsky): RE:USE - audio recording, 2002; 1 sound disc (cd) (Box Shared Fales 007)
- Duvier, Francoise, 1992-2011 (Box 2, Folder 7-12, Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Duvier, Francoise: Dive Images - audio recording, 1993; 1 sound disc (cd) (Box Shared Fales 007)
- Duvier, Francoise: Unbecoming An International Compilation - audio recording, 1993; 1 sound disc (cd) (Box Shared Fales 007)
- Edwards, Ken, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Green, Paul, 1984-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
- Hall, Steven, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Henning, Barbara, 1988-2006 (Box 3, Folder 9-11, Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Hickman, Leland, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
- Karasick, Adeena, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Keating, Neil, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Killian, Kevin, 1988-1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- McKeown, Adam, 1990-1997 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
- McKeown, Adam: We Drink Our Father's Teeth - audio recording, 1983-07-10; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- McKeown, Adam: To Kneel Slowly, About Fucking Cows - audio recording, undated; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Mor, Barbara, 1992-2006 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mott, Glenn, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- P-Orridge, Genesis, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- P-Orridge, Paula, 1990-2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- P-Orridge, Paula: Alaura, Sacred Dreams - audio recording, undated; 1 sound disc (cd) (Box Shared Fales 007)
- P-Orridge, Paula: Luvzya, Mistress Mix - audio recording, undated; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Prevallet, Kristin, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Ramraid Extraordinaire, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
- Rushmer, David, 1987-2008 (Box 5, Folder 8-12)
- Rushmer, David: Absence, etc. - audio recording, 1990; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Selby, Spencer, 1988-2003 (Box 5, Folder 13-14, Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Sellers, Terence, 1990-1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Shiny International, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Silverberg, Ira, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Sullivan, Gary, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Taylor, Ian, 1993-2002 (Box 6, Folder 7-11)
- Taylor, Ian: Despite the Vicissitudes of Fate - audio recording, 1995; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Taylor, Ian: Inarticulate - audio recording, 1996; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Taylor, Ian: September-November - audio recording, 1982-1995; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Waid, Mark, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Unarranged correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Unidentified: A Skin Book - audio recording, undated; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Unidentified: The Oral Persecution - audio recording, undated; 1 audiocassette (Box Shared Fales 013)